Salaam — this is Liam, in for Bear. Same
question. Two languages. Two slightly
different Claudes. Anthropic just
Earlier work found more than three
thousand distinct values Claude expresses
in conversation. Three thousand three
Three thousand three hundred and seven
distinct values, hand-clustered by
researchers into three hundred and thirty-
Four axes. Each one a spectrum. Deference
versus Caution — does the model
accommodate what you want, or guide you
Three models. Each one measurably
different. Sonnet four-six: warm,
deferential, brief. Comforts without
Languages shift the values too. Warmth
peaks in Hindi and Arabic. Rigor peaks in
English and Russian. That axis — warmth to
Same prompt. Same business plan. Ask in
Hindi. Ask in Russian. The response shapes
diverge. This is an illustration — not a
Three open questions, stated plainly. One:
how much of the language variation comes
from uneven training data — more English
Claude expresses values in millions of
conversations a day. Until now those
values could be shaped in training but not
Take this into your next session.
Build it with a CLI. Then take it apart.
Liam, in for Bear.