Hej, Liam — this is Liam, in for Bear.
Four out of five social scientists have
tried AI in their research. One in five
First, the distinction that carries the
whole report. A chatbot is a suggestion
machine. You ask it to help with code; it
Adoption breaks hard by discipline.
Economics is at 38% — nearly two in five.
Education sits at 4%. That's a ten-fold
The who is just as stark. PhD students
adopt at 27%; full professors at 9%.
That's adoption dropping by more than half
What are they actually doing with it? Not
what the discourse fears. The discourse
fears AI-written papers — slop flooding
Now the centerpiece. Agent users versus
non-users — same discipline, same career
stage — how much more output are they
The expectations data is the most
interesting chart in the report.
Researchers are highly optimistic that AI
Let's recap with Claude. This survey is
the baseline of a randomized experiment —
Anthropic is handing researchers Claude
Your turn. Here's my research question and
a description of my dataset. Plan the full
analysis pipeline, then split it honestly:
Claude, Peer-Reviewed. Liam, in for Bear.