What time is it in your city? Claude's
logs already know. News at 7 a.m. Recipes
at 6 p.m. Sleep advice at 5 a.m. Anthropic
Your workweek and Claude's workweek are
the same workweek. Personal conversations
jump from about 35 percent of usage on
One more data point. On April 14 — the day
before the US tax deadline — tax-related
conversations ran at eight times the
93 percent of Claude conversations produce
a concrete output. Anthropic now names
them: explanations, documents, guidance,
Here is the economic signal. Token usage
tracks wage level. Marketing managers at
eighty dollars an hour burn roughly two-
Same task, different leash. A blog post in
chat takes a median thirteen rounds of
back-and-forth. The same blog post in
Now the survey — nine-thousand-seven-
hundred respondents, privacy-preservingly
linked to their actual usage. About six in
Whose job changes? Everyone expects
responsibility shifts — forty-six percent
for themselves, fifty-five percent for
The delegation paradox. The people who
hand over the most are the most optimistic
— on all six dimensions of job quality.
One more split. Women are twelve percent
of the linked sample. They delegate seven-
point-three percentage points less, use
Last question in the survey: what do you
hope an economy shaped by AI looks like in
ten years? Over half: collaborate with AI
Let's recap with Claude. Anthropic's
Economic Index just got a heartbeat and a
taxonomy. Hourly logs, named artifacts,
Ask Claude: 'What share of my work tasks
could you do entirely on your own today —
and which ones should I never hand over?
Claude on the Clock. Liam, in for Bear.