My clone again. The short film introduced the free engine with eight voices. This is the reference cut: if you're thinking of using Kokoro for English narration, here are all twenty-eight voices — American then British, each carrying the pack's own grade, and every one closing on the same line so you can cast by ear. No lecture. Just the roster.
I'm Heart. American English, graded A minus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Alloy. American English, graded C plus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Aoede. American English, graded B minus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Bella. American English, graded A minus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Jessica. American English, graded B plus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Kore. American English, graded B. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Nicole. American English, graded B minus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Nova. American English, graded B. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm River. American English, graded C plus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Sarah. American English, graded C plus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Sky. American English, graded C. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Adam. American English, graded F plus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Echo. American English, graded C. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Eric. American English, graded C plus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Fenrir. American English, graded B plus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Liam. American English, graded C plus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Michael. American English, graded C plus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Onyx. American English, graded C. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Puck. American English, graded C plus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Santa. American English, graded D minus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Alice. British English, graded B. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Emma. British English, graded B minus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Isabella. British English, graded C plus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Lily. British English, graded B minus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Daniel. British English, graded B plus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Fable. British English, graded B. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm George. British English, graded C. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
I'm Lewis. British English, graded C plus. The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.
Heart again — the only A minus in the pack, so they gave me the close. That was all twenty-eight. The short film tells the story; this one is for casting. Subscribe for the series, and find the whole toolkit at www dot brutalist dot art. You bring the taste; the machine brings the hands.