In 1993, IBM scientists arranged forty-
eight iron atoms into a ring, then
photographed the space inside. Concentric
Last film: only waves that fit survive.
This film: trap a particle in a box, and
count the notes it's allowed to play.
A guitar string pinned at both ends plays
only whole humps — one, two, three.
Quantum swaps the string for probability
Schrödinger's equation in the box allows
any energy, until the walls speak. The
wave must die at both ends: sine of k L
The energy menu in one line: n squared
times a floor price, set by the particle's
mass and the width of its box. Nothing in
n counts the humps: one, two, three. h-bar
makes it quantum. Heavier particle or
wider box — every note in the menu drops.
An electron in a one-nanometer box: level
one costs point three-eight electron volts
— chemistry's scale. A marble in a
In 1913, Bohr decreed quantization — a
postulate. In 1926, Schrödinger derived it
from a differential equation and two
The levels climb as n squared — one, four,
nine, sixteen. Each higher note adds one
more zero-crossing: shorter wave, faster
And the bottom rung is never zero. A
trapped particle can't sit still —
stillness plus confinement violates the
Mix the two lowest notes and the
probability sloshes across the box every
three point seven femtoseconds. Motion is
Those rings at IBM are this exact
mathematics, photographed — standing waves
of probability, penned by forty-eight
Next: real walls are never infinitely
tall. Soften them, and particles begin to
leak straight through. Tunneling.