In 1887, Heinrich Hertz proved light is a
wave — the crowning triumph of classical
physics. The same year, he noticed
Ultraviolet light striking metal knocks
out sparks. Simple to see, impossible to
explain. This is the experiment that broke
By 1902, Philipp Lenard had shown the
sparks were electrons. By 1914, Robert
Millikan had measured every feature of
One: below a threshold frequency, nothing.
A blinding red arc lamp frees no electrons
from sodium. A dim ultraviolet lamp frees
Two: brighter light means more electrons —
but not faster ones. Double the
brightness, and each electron carries
Three: no delay. Emission begins within
nanoseconds, at any brightness above
threshold. Even the dimmest lamp never
Waves can't do any of this. A wave
delivers energy smoothly, everywhere at
once. Given enough time, any color should
Enter a twenty-six-year-old patent clerk
in Bern, in his miracle year: Albert
Einstein, taking the step Planck himself
Light isn't a smooth wave spread
everywhere. It arrives in whole packets —
Planck's chunks, now for light itself.
The rules become simple. One photon is
absorbed by one electron. Whole packet or
nothing — a photon cannot pay in
One line explains every impossible fact:
the electron's energy is the photon's
payment, minus the exit fee. Physicists
K max, the fastest electron's energy. H
nu, the photon's payment. And phi — the
work function — what the metal charges to
Ultraviolet on sodium: pay 4.13, fee 2.28
— the electron keeps 1.85 electron volts.
Green light pays 2.27. One hundredth
Threshold, explained: below the fee, no
photon can pay. Faster electrons from
bluer light: the payment is set by
Robert Millikan thought photons were
absurd. He spent two years trying to prove
Einstein wrong — freshly scraped metal
Every metal gave the same slope: h over e.
Einstein's equation fit perfectly.
Millikan published his own defeat — "in
Einstein's Nobel Prize came in 1921 — for
the photoelectric effect, not relativity.
Millikan's came two years later, for
Who was this patent clerk? A story of its
own. What he did to light — wave AND
particle at once — has no classical