Bonjour — this is Liam, in for Bear. Ask
Claude for art, and the first thing it
writes is a manifesto. Not the code. Not
A skill is a folder of instructions.
Claude reads it before it works. This
particular folder is called algorithmic-
Phase one: Claude must invent a named
movement. The skill lists its own
examples. 'Organic Turbulence' — chaos
The skill lists four other movements.
Quantum Harmonics — gridded particles with
evolving phase, interference building
Act three of the skill's own pipeline: the
conceptual seed. The skill demands a
hidden reference — the user's actual
Phase two: p5.js. And the Art Blocks
pattern — randomSeed and noiseSeed, both
set to the same value. Same seed,
The algorithm is the plate. The seed is
the print. Here is one algorithm, run with
nine different seeds. Visibly the same
The artifact viewer your audience sees.
Seed navigation, parameter sliders, color
controls, action buttons — that sidebar is
The Teardown moment. The skill repeats
certain phrases. 'Meticulously crafted
algorithm.' 'The product of deep
Let's recap with Claude. The algorithmic-
art skill is a two-phase pipeline:
philosophy first, code second. Phase one
Your turn. Here is the prompt — read it
with me. 'Create algorithmic art about
something I love. First write me the
Claude, Seeded. Liam, in for Bear.