You've made the videos. Now they have to
go live — and how you post them matters as
much as how you made them. This is posting
Here's the gap. A finished cut sitting on
your disk is not on YouTube. Crossing that
gap by hand — dragging each file into
So the toolkit posts through the YouTube
API instead. And everything travels with
the upload, straight from the beat sheet:
Always dry-run first. It prints the plan:
chapter one, What is Brutalist. Chapter
two, Installs. Chapter three, When Cowork
Then publish for real. Each upload comes
back with its link, and each is added to
the playlist in order. Three videos, live,
Quota is generous. Each upload costs
sixteen hundred units against ten thousand
a day — about six videos daily. Three was
Posting also wires the series together. By
default, every short's description points
to the intro video, and every long's
And there they are — the three this whole
video is built from. What is Brutalist,
posted as its review cut on purpose.
So here's the split, one more time. The
machine does the mechanical publish a
hand-upload loses — the description, the
And all of it — every command, every
error, every fix — is in one honest log.
Three uploaded, one bug found and fixed,
That's the short version. The full video
also covers what each video needs, find
playlist → upload → order and captions