You did the research this week. Here's how
to turn it into a video the world can
actually watch — using Claude and the
Six steps, one sitting. Your week's folder
goes in. The Brutalist system provides the
tools. Claude Code builds the video. You
Step one: put your week in a folder.
Notes, code, figures, data, the paper
draft, screenshots — all of it. That
Step two: get the Brutalist system. Email
hr@humanitarians.ai and you'll receive the
toolkit and setup help. Step three: open
Step four: give Claude the prompt — with
your specifics. Start from the generic
seed: create a claude-explainer in the
Step five: watch, then ask for changes.
Claude builds the video. Watch it.
Anything off — a wrong number, a pace that
Step six: publish to the channel. When
it's ready, use Gaurav's publishing script
— get it from hr@humanitarians.ai — to
Let's recap with Claude. Six steps to turn
your research week into a published video.
Your folder of notes, code, and figures.
Here's the prompt to run in your own
session. Here's my folder of this week's
research — describe what you did. Create a
How to Make Explainer Videos for Your
Research. Liam, for Humanitarians AI.