My clone, in English — the Romance languages belong to the cast. One video, four languages: three Spanish voices, three Brazilian Portuguese, two Italian, and one French — which happens to be the best-graded non-English voice in the whole pack, a B minus. The Spanish and Portuguese voices ship ungraded — the pack doesn't score them, so your ear is the only grade. Each voice says its name and the house line in its own language: the machine brings the hands — you bring the taste. Cast by ear.
Soy Dora, voz española.
La máquina pone las manos; el gusto lo pones tú.
[I'm Dora, Spanish voice. The machine puts the hands in — the taste is yours.]
Soy Alex, narrador español.
La máquina pone las manos; el gusto lo pones tú.
[I'm Alex, Spanish narrator. The machine puts the hands in — the taste is yours.]
Soy Santa, narrador español.
La máquina pone las manos; el gusto lo pones tú.
[I'm Santa, Spanish narrator. The machine puts the hands in — the taste is yours.]
Eu sou Dora, voz brasileira.
A máquina traz as mãos — o gosto é seu.
[I'm Dora, Brazilian voice. The machine brings the hands — the taste is yours.]
Eu sou Alex, locutor brasileiro.
A máquina traz as mãos — o gosto é seu.
[I'm Alex, Brazilian narrator. The machine brings the hands — the taste is yours.]
Eu sou Santa, locutor brasileiro.
A máquina traz as mãos — o gosto é seu.
[I'm Santa, Brazilian narrator. The machine brings the hands — the taste is yours.]
Sono Sara, voce italiana.
La macchina porta le mani — il gusto lo porti tu.
[I'm Sara, Italian voice. The machine brings the hands — the taste is yours.]
Sono Nicola, narratore italiano.
La macchina porta le mani — il gusto lo porti tu.
[I'm Nicola, Italian narrator. The machine brings the hands — the taste is yours.]
Je suis Siwis, voix française.
La machine apporte les mains — le goût, c'est vous.
[I'm Siwis, French voice. The machine brings the hands — the taste, it's you.]
The machine brings the hands — you bring the taste.