In the first six months of 1926, an
Austrian physicist published four papers
that rebuilt physics. At the center of all
Last film: psi squared gives the odds.
This film: the equation that moves psi.
Schrödinger's equation — the law of motion
The left side: how the wave function is
changing, right now. The right side: the
energy operator's verdict on the state.
i makes change into rotation, not decay.
H-bar sets the clock speed. And the
Hamiltonian — the energy operator —
Separate space from time: every energy
state becomes a spinning phase, turning at
energy over h-bar. One electron-volt: two
The trick is one guess: maybe space and
time separate. They do. The equation
splits — a trivial clock in time, an
Each energy state is a clock: real part,
imaginary part, spinning together. The
probability is the clock's shadow. The
You've seen this physics before — inside
every laser. Two mirrors, and only the
waves that fit exactly between them
Confinement plus wave equation equals a
menu. Only certain shapes fit the walls;
each shape carries its own energy. That
Mix two states and the spell breaks: the
shadow moves. The blend sloshes at the
beat between their energies — while the
And the mathematics? A century old.
Fourier proved these building blocks
complete in 1822 — for heat flow. Quantum
Who was Erwin Schrödinger? He found the
equation in six months, and spent decades
uneasy about what it meant. His doubt