This is the ElevenLabs version. The same video exists voiced by Suno — the link is in the description. You are the blind test.
Every video in this series speaks. And until today, every word of it cost ElevenLabs credits. This is the cost test: the same narration, voiced two different ways — and the video you're watching is the experiment.
Here's the itch. ElevenLabs is metered. Every character of every beat, every retake, every regeneration draws down the same tank. It's a great voice — but a series that talks a lot pays a lot.
The challenger is Suno. My voice lives there too — uploaded once. It leans a little speak-song, but for spoken word it's clear. And the pricing shape is different: not a meter, a flat generation — and one generation can carry an entire video's narration.
So the toolkit grew a second voice path. Art suno takes the same beat sheet — the single source of truth — and writes the narration out as text files, one per four thousand characters, because that's the size of Suno's lyrics box. No beat is ever split across a file boundary.
Every beat gets one meta tag above it: spoken word. Not once at the top — above every single beat. Because even when your only style note is spoken word, Suno will sometimes decide your sentence deserves a melody. The tag keeps it speaking.
The human loop is three moves. Paste a file into Suno. Generate with your voice and download the vocal-only stem — no music bed. Then drop it in the pantry. The pantry is where human-made media always lands in this toolkit.
Then art suno-slice cuts the stem at the silences between beats — one mp3 per beat — and measures every one. If the segments don't match the beats, it refuses to touch anything and tells you which knob to turn. No quiet failures.
And here's the part that matters. The slices land in exactly the slots ElevenLabs would have filled. Same files, same measured durations, same beat sheet. Downstream — the renders, the captions, the shorts, the publish — nothing knows which engine spoke. The voice is a plug.
The exact numbers from this build are on screen — what this video's narration cost through the meter, and what it cost flat. The shape of the answer was never in doubt: metered pricing scales with how much you talk. Flat pricing doesn't. A talkative series feels that difference on every single video.
It isn't a free lunch. The metered voice is steadier — take after take sounds the same. The flat voice can drift musical, and you pay in retakes and slicing instead of credits. Cheap has a workflow tax. The question is whether the tax is smaller than the bill.
So here's the split, one more time. The machine will voice every beat either way — meter or flat, it doesn't care. What it can't do is decide what you're willing to sound like. I listened to both takes of this very video. One of them is playing right now — because I picked it. You bring the taste.
And all of it — every generation, every credit, every retake — is in one honest log. Two engines, one narration, real numbers. This video was built from that log.
That's the cost test. Subscribe to follow the series, and find the whole toolkit at www dot brutalist dot art. You bring the taste; the machine brings the hands — and now, either voice.