In 1924, a doctoral student handed Paris a
thesis so strange the committee nearly
rejected it. They asked Einstein. Einstein
His name was Louis de Broglie, and his
idea takes one sentence: if light waves
act like particles, then particles should
Einstein had shown light carries momentum
— waves behaving like particles. De
Broglie simply reversed the arrow:
The whole thesis is one line: wavelength
equals h over momentum. The faster or
heavier the thing, the shorter its wave.
Lambda, the wavelength of matter itself.
P, the momentum — mass times velocity. And
h, Planck's constant again — the same tiny
An electron accelerated through 150 volts:
wavelength one tenth of a nanometer.
Exactly the spacing between atoms in a
In New Jersey, Clinton Davisson and Lester
Germer were firing electrons at nickel,
recording boring, featureless scatter.
Cleaning the nickel with heat turned it
into a single crystal — orderly rows of
atoms. The boring scatter vanished. Sharp
Electrons at 54 volts should diffract like
a wave of point one six seven nanometers.
Run it through Bragg's law: the peak lands
Decades later in Japan, Akira Tonomura
made it undeniable. He fired electrons
through a splitter one at a time — never
Each electron lands as a single dot. Ten
dots: random. Two hundred: faint clumps.
Six thousand: stripes forming. Seventy
The electrons never touched each other.
Each one's wave explored both paths at
once and interfered with itself. The dot
So why don't you diffract through a
doorway? Compute it: seventy kilograms
walking equals a wavelength of ten to the
That's twenty orders of magnitude smaller
than a proton. Quantum mechanics doesn't
switch off at human scale — its stripes
The frontier keeps moving: sixty-atom
carbon balls diffracted in 1999. Molecules
of two thousand atoms by 2019. The wave
Who was this doctoral student? French
aristocracy, a history degree, a Nobel
Prize five years after the thesis they
Next: if every particle is a wave — what,
exactly, is waving?