Profile, Kaustubha Venkata Eluri. Most AI
projects don't fail because the model is
wrong. They fail in the gap between 'works
Picture two platforms. On the left:
development. Green metrics, curated data,
a model that hits its numbers. On the
Here's the industry blind spot. A model
that works in isolation is a curiosity.
The accuracy is real. The demo is
Four projects, all different domains, one
discipline. RapidTriage AI: clinical
decision support where latency and
Here's what production actually demands.
An API fails — not sometimes, regularly.
One branch: the system collapses. Red from
The industry celebrates the benchmark
improvement and the novel architecture.
The accepted paper. The citation count.
Kaustubha Venkata Eluri is at Northeastern
University — Teaching Assistant in Mobile
App Development, Academic Peer Mentor,
Let's recap with Claude. Trustworthiness
is not a model property — it's a system
property. A model that works in isolation
Here's a prompt to run on your own
project. Audit my ML project for the gap
between works in the lab and works when
The Engineer Who Stayed. Liam, in for
Bear.