Before you make a single video with this
toolkit, you set up — once. Keys,
credentials, a couple of tools. This is
Everything lives in one file: dot env, at
the root. You make it by copying the
example, then fill in only the lines you
Like this. Copy dot env dot example to dot
env. It's gitignored, so your keys never
get committed. Open it, fill in what you
One thing isn't just a key. YouTube uses
Google OAuth — a pair of JSON files, not
an API key. They live in a per-channel
Two tools need a word of explanation.
First, N-P-X. It runs a Node package's
command-line tool without installing it
That's how every Remotion render happens
here. N-P-X remotion render. Same command
on every machine, always the version this
Second, pip — Python's installer. It pulls
the libraries the scripts import: Manim
for animation, librosa for timing, Pillow
And a virtual environment — a venv. It's
an isolated Python: its own interpreter,
its own packages, in a folder inside the
Make it once, activate it, and ask the
doctor. Setup prints a readiness table —
green means the libraries are exactly
Here's the part that matters for Claude
Code. When it builds a video, it runs
those scripts as python-three. So Claude
Four services cost money, and none is
required to start. ElevenLabs does voice
and narration — the important one.
Here's the single biggest time-saver in
the whole toolkit. Record about thirty
minutes of your own voice, once, and clone
Yes — the clone mispronounces some words.
So do I. It's a review note like any
other: catch it, spell that one word out
When you're set, two commands tell you
exactly where you stand. Setup, for the
dependencies. And art keys — it checks
That's setup. Do the voice clone — it's
the highest-leverage thirty minutes you'll
spend. Subscribe to follow the series, and