This is my voice — the ElevenLabs clone that's narrated every video in this series. It's good. It's also metered. So for the rest of this video, I'm handing the microphone to a cast that costs exactly nothing. They live on this laptop. And they have names.
I'm Bella. I'm a Kokoro voice — an eighty-two-million-parameter open model, Apache licensed, running locally on the same machine that's rendering these graphics. No A P I. No meter. No bill. I'm what free sounds like.
I'm Sarah. Here's why we plug straight in: a voice engine in this toolkit is just something that fills one mp3 per beat and measures it. Same files, same durations, same beat sheet. Downstream, nothing knows I'm not the expensive one.
I'm Adam. On the official report card, I'm graded F plus — the pack grades its own voices, and it doesn't flatter us. They let me say this beat anyway. That's the honest record: free has a range, and you should hear the bottom of it.
I'm Michael. The command is one line — and the casting is one field. This very beat says voice: A M underscore Michael. Change the field, change the reader. That's the whole workflow.
I'm Emma — one of the British voices. There are twenty-eight of us in English: twenty American, eight British, graded A to F by the pack itself. And the wider pack speaks nine languages — fifty-four voices in all. You've just heard an A minus, a C plus, and an F plus. Casting is taste — and now taste is free.
I'm George. The strongest use isn't the final cut — it's the draft. Free narration means real timings, real conforms, a watchable preview, before a single paid credit is spent. Greybox — for the ears.
I'm Puck. Now the catch, honestly: none of us is you. Kokoro doesn't clone. When the video carries your name and your channel, the voice should be yours — metered or flat. When it doesn't, we work free.
And I'm Santa. Graded D minus. Ho ho. You get what you pay for — except you didn't pay.
So the roster is three engines now. Metered — the clone, steadiest, priced by the character. Flat — your voice through Suno, one generation per video. And free — us. The machine will voice every beat either way. Who speaks is taste, and taste is yours.
That's the free voice option. Subscribe to follow the series, and find the whole toolkit at www dot brutalist dot art. You bring the taste; the machine brings the hands — and now, a cast.