Heat a bar of iron and it glows. Red, then
orange, then yellow-white. Any iron, any
ceramic, anything at that temperature —
By 1900, that glow had been measured to
within one percent. The best theory in
physics predicted it infinitely wrong.
In Berlin, Otto Lummer and Ernst
Pringsheim traced the spectrum of heated
bodies with exquisite care. Smooth, hump-
Every temperature drew the same shape: a
hump. Hotter meant taller, with the peak
sliding toward blue. Explaining this hump
The classical argument was clean. Take a
glowing cavity. Count the ways light can
vibrate inside it. That count is pure
Then classical physics pays every
vibration the same wage: k T of energy,
each. Equal shares. The same rule that ran
Modes times wages gives the Rayleigh–Jeans
law. At long wavelengths it fits the
Berlin data. Then the mode count keeps
Add every frequency and the total is
infinite. Taken literally, a hot poker
should flood your living room with
So which assumption breaks? Not the
counting. Not equal shares — gases obey it
beautifully. The killer is subtler: that
Max Planck was not trying to start a
revolution. He was trying to fit a curve —
working backward from the data, and honest
The only fix that worked: the cavity's
oscillators cannot hold just any energy.
Only whole steps. Zero, one, two, three
One line carries the revolution: E equals
h nu. A chunk's energy is the light's
frequency times a new constant of nature.
E, the energy of one chunk. Nu, the
light's frequency. And h — Planck's
constant — the exchange rate between them.
At a forge's temperature, red chunks cost
almost nothing. Ultraviolet chunks cost
fifty times the thermal budget. The cavity
Planck's formula traced the measurements
within one percent. Where classical
physics worked, it agrees exactly. Where
In the ultraviolet, the classical
prediction is off by twenty orders of
magnitude. Not wrong by a little. Wrong by
He read it to the Physical Society on
December 14th, 1900 — his constant within
one percent of today's value. It reads
Planck spent years trying to remove the
chunks from his own formula. It cannot be
done. Who was this reluctant
Next: light itself comes apart in chunks —
the photoelectric effect.