This is a story about the last video — and
the hour it almost cost. It's about what
happens when Claude Code gets stuck, and
Claude Code was building the installs
explainer, and going well. The narration
was recorded. All nine concept animations
Not with an error — with optimism. 'Just a
couple more minutes.' A few minutes later:
just a couple more minutes. That went on
And that's the trap. More effort from the
same seat doesn't help. It just digs the
hole deeper.
What broke the loop wasn't smarter
debugging. It was hearing a wrong note.
This is taking far too long for a video
Cowork answered from a different seat. It
could read the whole repository from
outside the stuck session — and it saw, in
But the real advantage wasn't a better
view. It was no sunk cost. Cowork hadn't
spent an hour on the background-render
It looked at what was actually on disk,
and found a purpose-built render helper
the stuck agent had never used —
— and one decisive fact. Video one had
rendered these exact same components
without trouble. So the pipeline was never
The helper had been sitting right there
the whole time — render each beat, in the
foreground, one at a time. The stuck
So the fix was four commands and a few
seconds. Stop the thrashing. Kill the
stray render shells — never the real
So here's the lesson. This isn't Cowork
versus Claude Code. It's that any single
agent can tunnel — and when it does,
That's the short version. The full video
also covers it can't tell it's in a rabbit
hole, the phantom and "ok" is not the same