In 1926, in Göttingen, Max Born wrote a
paper about particles colliding.
Correcting the proofs, he added a
Last film ended with a question: if every
particle is a wave, what exactly is
waving? The answer has a name. The wave
That same year, Erwin Schrödinger produced
an equation for a new object: psi. It said
exactly how psi moves. It never said what
Here it is, from our own simulation: a
blue hump drifting and spreading, an
orange ripple running inside it. Beautiful
Born's draft said the probability of
finding the particle is proportional to
psi. The footnote fixed it: not psi — psi
Born's rule is one line: the probability
of finding the particle in a region is the
integral of psi squared over that region.
Psi is the wave function. Psi squared is a
density — probability per nanometer, like
population per square mile. The integral
Take psi as a falling exponential. Within
one width of center: eighty-six percent.
At the peak the density reads two per
Here's the strange part: psi is complex.
Two packets, identical blue humps. One
moves left, one moves right. The hump
That's not decoration. Schrödinger's
equation has an i built in — erase the
imaginary part and take one time-step: it
And when the blue hump spreads, the
particle is not smearing out. Detect it:
one dot. Repeat the experiment thousands
The wave function is not the particle. It
is the rule for the odds. Every histogram
ever measured agrees with the footnote.
Who was Max Born? When Einstein wrote that
God does not play dice, the letter was
addressed to Born. His Nobel came twenty-
Next: the equation that moves the wave
function — where it came from, and why it
works.