This is an experiment. This is 'What is
Brutalist?' — the first in a series on
making videos with Claude. Every video in
One quick thing before we start. You'll
notice a small grey label in the corner of
every shot. That's the review label. It
You can ask an AI to make a whole video in
one click. And most of the time, what
comes back is slop — clean, rendered, and
Here's the asymmetry that explains it.
Claude cannot watch the video. It has
never sat in the audience.
So it can't tell you whether a joke lands,
whether an opening is interesting or
merely competent, whether the idea
But flip it around. Claude is superhuman
at the build. It writes Remotion and Manim
faster and more correctly than you ever
A human spending twenty hours hunting a
render bug is twenty hours thrown away —
that's exactly the work the machine is
So the two ways to get it wrong sit at the
extremes. Push the work onto the human,
and you're debugging TypeScript at 2 a.m.
Brutalist holds the line in the middle.
And the line has a name: you are the
conductor.
You decide what the piece is. You listen
for the wrong note. You own the result.
The machine — an extraordinary player —
Here's that loop — live, from building
this very video. Look: that box was too
narrow, the text spilled over the edge. I
Here's how it actually works. Every video
is a beat sheet — one beat per moment.
That sheet is the heart; everything else
First, fill-in: the machine renders every
beat it can make — a Manim animation, a
Remotion graphic, a title card. If the
What's left is only the beats a machine
honestly can't make — real footage, an
archival image, a performance. For those
None of this needs a black box. Ask the
doctor what you can make right now.
Then conduct. List the skills, see what a
video still needs, and compile.
That's Brutalist. The machine does what
machines are superhuman at. You do what
only an audience can. Every video in this
Subscribe to follow the series, and find
the whole toolkit at www dot brutalist dot
art. You bring the taste. The machine