Salaam — this is Liam, in for Bear. Last
December, Anthropic pointed an AI
interviewer at its own users and asked one
Eighty thousand five hundred and eight
people. A hundred and fifty-nine
countries. Seventy languages. Interviewed
What do people hope for? Professional
excellence tops the list at eighteen point
eight percent. But read the full ranking
A software engineer in Japan put it
plainly.
Has AI delivered? Eighty-one percent said
yes — it has taken a step toward their
vision. Productivity dominates at thirty-
One worker in the dataset sent a hundred
and fifty messages over three months — to
a text-to-speech bot they built themselves
What do people worry about? Unreliability
tops the fears at twenty-six point seven
percent — that's the only tension where
A freelancer in France described the
feeling exactly.
The centerpiece finding: hope and fear
don't divide people into camps. They
coexist inside the same person. Five
An American put the fear plainly.
Sixty-seven percent net positive globally.
No country below sixty percent. But the
distribution of concern is not uniform. In
Plot jobs-and-economy concern against
negative sentiment and the split is
geographic. Wealthier regions cluster top
There are no AI optimists and no AI
pessimists. There are people organized
around what they value, holding hope and
Take this into your next session.
Build it with a CLI. Then take it apart.
Liam, in for Bear.