Six hours into the hackathon, her app
worked. Then a user asked one question —
and she told her team to throw the working
Picture the six-hour mark. A symptom
tracker, clean demo, on track to finish.
Working code, real progress. Then a user
The clearest evidence of that attention:
MediPedia. A local RAG medical-FAQ chatbot
built on a budget of zero. Ollama running
MediPedia is one chip on a pattern that
runs across everything she builds.
SecureStream AI: real-time privacy
In parallel, she was building the room
that sixty-plus women in tech needed to
exist. Hub Leader for Rewriting the Code
The official number: GPA 3.717. MS in
Information Systems, Northeastern,
December 2025. The number is real. Here's
The pivot paid off. FinFluent was the
DreamAI 2025 finalist pitch — Aditi led
it. Every element traces to something
Aditi Deodhar. MS Information Systems,
Northeastern University College of
Engineering, December 2025. AI Engineer.
Let's recap with Claude. The willingness
to stop — to discard working code six
hours into a competition and rebuild
Here's a prompt to run on your own
project. 'I'm building something that
technically works. Interview me like a
The Cost of the Pivot. Liam, in for Bear.