Hei — this is Liam, in for Bear. A
frontier model is a vast store of
knowledge. Some of it heals. Some of it
Here is the constraint. You want three
things at once: lock dangerous knowledge
surgically, still let trusted users reach
Today's safety approach guards the output.
Refusal training. Input and output
classifiers. All of it sits on the exit
The obvious alternative: filter dual-use
data out of pretraining. Virology text
never enters the model. But this commits
GRAM — Gradient-Routed Auxiliary Modules —
takes a different route. At every
Transformer layer, you attach extra
Training has two kinds of passes. On
general text, gradient flows through the
whole network — everyone learns. On
After training: delete the module. The
capability disappears with it. The rest of
the model is completely unchanged. Or
Four categories. Each can be on or off.
One training run produces sixteen
deployable configurations — the full
Three tests of rising realism. Test one:
synthetic children's stories, topic-
tagged. GRAM can forget any topic on
Test two: real web, code, and science data
— four actual domains. Delete the module,
the capability score drops. General
Test three: scale. Seven model sizes from
fifty million to five billion parameters.
At every size, GRAM matches filtering. And
Honest caveats, stated plainly. This is
early preliminary research — not in any
production Claude model. Testing reached
Take this into your next session. Liam, in
for Bear.
An Off Switch for Dangerous Knowledge.
Research: AE Studio times Anthropic. Liam,
in for Bear.